A Guide to the W. W. Scott papers, 1891-1957
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
W. W. Scott papers, 1891-1957
The Library of Virginia
44929, 50464
.45 cubic feet and 1 box
W. W. Scott
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Ann Thornton of New York, New York.
Biographical Information
William Wallace Scott was born 10 April 1845 in Orange County, Virginia, and he attended the Virginia Military Institute. He enlisted in the Confederate Army 1 December 1863 and served in Company H, 4th Virginia Cavalry, also known as the Black Horse Cavalry. Scott was captured by Union forces in April 1865, but escaped; eventually being paroled in Charlottesville, Virginia, on 1 May 1865. After the war, Scott became a lawyer and editor. He served as the law librarian for the state of Virginia, and published works on Virginia and its history. Scott married Claudia Marshall Willis (1846-1912) 29 September 1869, and they had nine children. Scott died 16 January 1929, and was buried in Maplewood Cemetery in Gordonsville, Virginia.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1891-1957, of W. W. Scott (1845-1929) of Orange County and Richmond, Virginia, consisting of accounts, advertisements, charts, deeds, envelopes, epitaphs, essays, letters, notes, poems, promissory notes, receipts, reminiscences, satires, and speeches, mainly concerning Virginia and Orange County history, including Scott's HISTORY OF ORANGE COUNTY, VA; and James Madison (1751-1836). Papers also contain correspondence to and from Scott's son Philip H. Scott (1873-1962); receipts for purchases and payments by Scott; copyright for a book by Scott and W. G. Stanard; poems by Samuel Taylor Coleridge, Philip Slaughter, Will Henry Thompson, and unknown; an epitaph for Jane Webb in Old Blue Run Church; and the condensed profile for the Chesapeake and Ohio Railway in 1908.
Contents List
- Letter, 11 November 1891, from James Keegan to C. W. Woolfolk. (Folder 1)
- Letter, 22 December 1893, from George J. Hemphill to C. H. Simonton. (Folder 2)
- Letter, 20 May 1898, from D. C. Richardson to W. W. Scott. (Folder 3)
- Letter, 30 April 1900, from Holmes Conrad to W. W. Scott. (Folder 4)
- Letter, 16 June 1900, from R. R. Howison to W. W. Scott. (Folder 5)
- Letter, 24 July 1900, from unknown to W. W. Scott. (Folder 6)
- Letter, 12 October 1900, from R. R. Howison to W. W. Scott. (Folder 7)
- Letter, 20 December 1900, from Gaillard Hunt to W. W. Scott. (Folder 8)
- Letter, 1900, from Gaillard Hunt to W. W. Scott. (Folder 9)
- Letter, 1900, from Gaillard Hunt to W. W. Scott. (Folder 10)
- Letter, 5 January 1901, from Gaillard Hunt to W. W. Scott. (Folder 11)
- Letter, 23 April 1901, from William J. Bok to W. W. Scott. (Folder 12)
- Letter, 18 November 1903, from Thomas T. Munford to W. W. Scott. (Folder 13)
- Letter, [-----]1906, from Thomas T. Munford to W. W. Scott. (Folder 14)
- Letter, 24 April 1907, from from J. E. Bradford to W. W. Scott. (Folder 15)
- Letter, 11 May 1907, from G. W. Barbour to W. W. Scott. (Folder 16)
- Letter, 15 June 1907, from Sallie Fitzhugh Parran to W. W. Scott. (Folder 17)
- Letter, [24 June] 1907, from M. M. G. Pannill to W. W. Scott. (Folder 18)
- Letter, 4 July 1907, from E. L. Goss to W. W. Scott. (Folder 19)
- Letter, 3 October 1907, from Alexander Cameron to W. W. Scott. (Folder 20)
- Letter, [1907], from John S. Chapman to W. W. Scott. (Folder 21)
- Letter, 16 June 1908, from R. C. Stearnes to W. W. Scott. (Folder 22)
- Letter, 13 September 1909, from Maryus Jones to W. W. Scott. (Folder 23)
- Letter, [8 October 1915], from Katherine Isham Keith to W. W. Scott. (Folder 24)
- Letter, 30 December 1915, from Katherine Isham Keith to W. W. Scott. (Folder 25)
- Letter, 3 May 1922, from Nelly C. Willis to W. W. Scott. (Folder 26)
- Letter, 1 October 1922, from Nelly C. Willis to W. W. Scott. (Folder 27)
- Letter, 7 May 1924, from Armistead C. Gordon to W. W. Scott. (Folder 28)
- Letter, 3 June 1924, from Trist Wood to W. W. Scott. (Folder 29)
- Letter, 20 July 1924, from Trist Wood to W. W. Scott. (Folder 30)
- Letter, 7 June 1951, from J. G. de Rouhlac Hamilton to Philip H. Scott. (Folder 31)
- Letter and agreement, 1 November 1951, from Anna Brook Allan for James W. Patton to Philip H. Scott. (Folder 32)
- Letter, 21 December 1957, from [Philip H. Scott] to [Ralph] Ketcham. (Folder 33)
- Letter, no date, from Thomas T. Munford to W. W. Scott. (Folder 34)
- Letter, no date, from M. M. G. Pannill to W. W. Scott. (Folder 35)
- Letter, no date, from [Philip H. Scott] to unknown. (Folder 36)
- Envelope, 12 September [-----], from Thomas T. Munford to W. W. Scott. (Folder 37)
- Envelope, no date, to W. W. Scott. (Folder 38)
- Deed, 1 March 1899 and recorded April 1899, for property in Orange County from A. C. Berryman and Helen K. Berryman to Claudia M. Scott, Philip H. Scott, and Robert L. M. Scott, trustees. (Folder 39)
- Deed of agreement, 1 May 1900, of W. W. Scott and Robert L. M. Scott with A. C. Berryman. (Folder 40)
- Receipt, 13 October 1903, from S. S. P. Patteson, chairman of committee, Library Board, Virginia State Library to W. W. Scott for return of funds. (Folder 41)
- Receipt, 27 February 1906, from R. H. Harris to W. W. Scott for payment for burial of Wyclif Scott. (Folder 42)
- Receipt, 8 March 1906, from J. N. Waddell to W. W. Scott for payment for shoe repair. (Folder 43)
- Account, 12 June 1908, of W. W. Scott with the Everett Waddy Company. (Folder 44)
- Receipt and letter, 17-18 July 1911, from Herman Schmidt to W. W. Scott for purchase of groceries. (Folder 45)
- Copyright, 7 April 1894, from A. R. Spofford, Library of Congress, to W. S. Scott and W. G. Stanard for The Capitol of Virginia. (Folder 46)
- Promissory notes, 15 January and 29 July 1895, of E. B. Wood and the Gottchalk Company. (Folder 47)
- Recollections of General Jackson. (Folder 48)
- Biographical notes on John Robertson. (Folder 49)
- Speech at the dedication of the Blind Preacher [James Waddell] Monument. (Folder 50)
- Notes on E. L. Powell, [ca. 1908]. (Folder 51)
- Orange County, Virginia, notes--French and Indian War and Revolutionary War veterans. (Folder 52)
- Speech at the unveiling of the monument fo the Confederate dead of Orange. (Folder 53)
- A Fugh Hieughs, a poem to Hugh Hamilton 22 March 1908. (Folder 54)
- A Prude's Opinion. (Folder 55)
- Has Beens,ca. 1909. (Folder 56)
- $1,000,000 Reward! Strayed, Lost, or Stolen! A Jeffersonian Democrat with Taft Proclivities. (Folder 57)
- The Undertaker. (Folder 58)
- Notes on the history of Virginia. (Folder 59)
- History of Orange County, Va., advertisement, 1907. (Folder 60)
- Child of My Muse by Samuel Taylor Coleridge. (Folder 61)
- Lines on Blandford Church by Philip Slaughter. (Folder 62)
- High Tide at Gettysburg by Will Henry Thompson. (Folder 63)
- I've done so much to be forgiven [first line], 27 April, 1920. (Folder 64)
- Gravestone inscription for Jane Webb at Old Blue Run Church, Orange County. (Folder 65)
- Richmond Enquirer, 26 August 1862. Transferred to the Newspaper Project, issue can be found on newspaper microfilm reel 23a. (Folder 66)
- Condensed profile of the Chesapeake and Ohio Railway, 1908. (Folder 67)
- Unidentified manuscript fragments. (Folder 68)
- Miscellaneous scraps and fragments. (Folder 69)